Register of the Richard V. Allen papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Richard V. Allen papers
1948-1999
2007C17
Hoover Institution Archives
122 manuscript boxes, 10 oversize boxes (60.0 linear feet)
Contains correspondence, speeches, interviews, legal files, subject files, photographs, audio and video recordings, clippings, and notes relating to Allen's work in American politics and government. As a specialist in security and foreign policy, Allen worked on the Nixon and Reagan campaigns and held posts on the National Security Council under each of them. Topics of note include: Ronald Reagan, George H. W. Bush, Richard Nixon, foreign policy, national security, political campaigns, Iran hostage crisis, Republican National Committee, libel and media abuses, Korea, and Taiwan.
Allen, Richard V.
Access
The collection is open for research, though the following boxes are closed during the lifetime of Richard V. Allen: boxes 3, 13-18 from the Correspondence series, boxes 36-42 from the Campaign and transition files, boxes 51-53 from the White House files, boxes 60-61 from the Committee files, box 77 from the Legal files, and boxes 85-88 from the Publicity series. The audiocassette of the Albosta/Debategate interview of Richard Allen in box 105 is also closed.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Ronald Reagan subject collection, Hoover Institution Archives
Robert E. McCarthy papers, Hoover Institution Archives
1981 Presidential Inaugural Committee records, Hoover Institution Archives
Joseph Shattan papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Fred Charles Iklé papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Annelise Graebner Anderson papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Deaver and Hannaford records, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1 January 1936 Born, Collingswood, New Jersey
1957 B.A. from University of Notre Dame
28 December 1957 Marries Patricia Ann Mason
1958 M.A. in Political Science from University of Notre Dame
1958-1961 Lecturer, University of Maryland, Overseas Division
1961-1962 Assistant professor of social sciences, Georgia Institute of Technology
1962-1966 Research principal and chairman of study program on communism, Georgetown University Center for Strategic Studies
1963 (Editor with David M. Abshire) National Security: Political, Military, and Economic Strategies in the Decade Ahead, Praeger
1964 Publication of Peaceful Coexistence: A Communist Blueprint for Victory, American Bar Association (Co-author) East-West Trade: Its Strategic Implications, Center for Strategic Studies, Georgetown University
1966 Publication of Peace or Peaceful Coexistence? American Bar Association
1966-1968 Senior staff member, Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace
1967-1968 Senior foreign policy advisor, Nixon-Agnew campaign committee
1967 Author (with Hal Bartlett and Kenneth Colegrove) of Democracy and Communism: Theory and Action, Van Nostrand
1969 Senior staff member, National Security Council (Editor) Yearbook on International Communist Affairs, Hoover Institute Press
1969-1971 Vice president of International Resources Ltd.
1970-1972 Member, Presidential Commission on International Trade and Economic Policy
1971-1972 Deputy executive director, Council on International Economic Policy, and deputy assistant to the President on International Economic Affairs
1972-1981 President of Potomac International Corp.
1978-1980 Senior foreign policy advisor to Ronald Reagan
1981-1982 Assistant for national security affairs (National Security Advisor) to President Reagan
1982- President, Richard V. Allen Co. Distinguished fellow and chairman, Asian Studies Center, Heritage Foundation
1983- Senior fellow, Hoover Institution
Scope and Content of Collection
The Richard V. Allen papers contain correspondence, speeches, interviews, legal files, subject files, photographs, audio and video recordings, clippings, and notes relating to Allen's work in United States politics and government. As a specialist in security and foreign policy, Allen worked on the Nixon and Reagan campaigns and held posts in the National Security Council under each of them. Topics of note include: Ronald Reagan, George H. W. Bush, Richard Nixon, trade policy, foreign policy, national security, political campaigns, Iran hostage crisis, Republican National Committee, libel and media abuses, Korea, and Taiwan.
The Allen papers provide evidence of Richard V. Allen's longstanding relationship with the Republican Party, his working relationship with two presidents, and his subsequent role in the public sphere as a consultant and commentator. Allen began his career in academia and spent the bulk of the 1960s writing about communism. This period is not well documented in the collection. This background aided Allen as he left academia for the chance to shape public policy; Allen worked on the presidential campaigns of Richard Nixon and Ronald Reagan as an expert in foreign policy and national security, then assumed responsibilities at the National Security Council under each of the two presidents. The Correspondence and Campaign and transition files document Allen's work for both President Nixon and President Reagan, and the White House files provide further details of Allen's tenure as National Security Advisor under President Reagan.
Allen's continuous interest in political life and public policy is reflected in the Committee files, which document his relationships in the 1970s with the Council on International Economic Policy and Republican National Committee, and in the Subject files, which encompass a variety of topics of interest to Allen including the Iran hostage crisis and Presidents Nixon, Reagan, and G.H.W. Bush. The Speeches and writings, Publicity, and Audiovisual material series all document Allen's role in the public sphere as analyst and commentator, especially after he left his position as National Security Advisor in 1981. The Legal files record Allen's testimony before various congressional committees, and also cover his struggles with the press in the wake of his resignation from public office. Together, the Calendars series and the Invitations series illustrate both Allen's work and social life.
The Photographs series provides an excellent cross-section of Allen's entire career. It includes materials depicting Allen's work at the White House, his appearances on the television show Inside Washington, his travels to Asia, speaking engagements, social events, and visits with leaders of other countries, especially Taiwan and South Korea.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 13 series: Correspondence, 1962-1987; Campaign and transition files, 1967-1984; White House files, 1979-1989; Subject files, 1968-1999; Committee files, 1969-1984; Speeches and writings, 1961-1999; Legal files, 1971-1999; Publicity Materials, 1945-1999; Calendars, 1971-1998; Invitations, 1981, 1986; Declassified U.S. government records, 1975-1980; Photographs, 1968-1999; Audiovisual material, 1948-1999.
National Security Council (U.S.); Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994.; Reagan, Ronald.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Audiotapes.; Iran Hostage Crisis, 1979-1981.; Photographs.; Presidents--United States--Election--1968.; Presidents--United States--Election--1980.; United States--Defenses.; United States--Foreign relations--1945-1989.; United States--Foreign relations--1981-1989.; United States--Politics and government.; Video tapes.
- Correspondence, 1962-1987 (Box-folder 1-21)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes incoming and outgoing correspondence, primarily dating from Allen's work on the Nixon and Reagan presidential campaigns and administrations. Also includes a small amount of material predating Allen's policy work and from the period between Nixon and Reagan. Correspondence is divided into three subseries: Chronological, Alphabetical, and Public response to leave and resignation correspondence.
  - Chronological correspondence, 1962-1987. (Box-folder 1-10)
    Contains correspondence, mainly copies of outgoing letters. Includes Allen's personal correspondence, official correspondence, correspondence with Ambassadors and members of Congress, and correspondence regarding his resignation in 1981. Arranged chronologically.
    - Personal/General, 1962-1967 (Box-folder 1: 1)
    - Personal/General, 1968 June (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - Personal/General, 1968 July (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - Personal/General, 1968 August (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - Personal/General, 1968 September (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - Personal/General, 1968 October (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - Personal/General, 1968 November (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - Personal/General, 1968 December (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - Election congratulations, 1968 (Box-folder 1: 9-11)
    - Personal/General, 1969 January (Box-folder 1: 12)
    - Personal/General, 1969 February (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - Personal/General, 1969 March (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - Personal/General, 1969 April (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - Personal/General, 1969 May (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - Personal/General, 1969 June (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - Personal/General, 1969 July (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - Personal/General, 1969 August (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - Personal/General, 1969 September (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - Personal/General, 1969 October (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - Official, 1969 January (Box-folder 2: 10)
    - Official, 1969 February (Box-folder 2: 11)
    - Official, 1969 April (Box-folder 2: 12)
    - Official, 1969 May (Box-folder 2: 13)
    - Official, 1969 June (Box-folder 2: 14)
    - Official, 1969 July (Box-folder 2: 15)
    - Official, 1969 August (Box-folder 2: 16)
    - Official, 1969 October (Box-folder 2: 17)
    - International Resources, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 2: 18)
    - Humphrey, Hubert, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 2: 19)
    - Azores, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 2: 20)
    - King Resources, 1978 (Box-folder 2: 21)
    - Correspondence, CLOSED, 1981 (Box-folder 3)
    - Ambassadorial correspondence, 1981 (Box-folder 4: 1-3)
    - Congressional correspondence: House, 1981 (Box-folder 4: 4-5)
    - Congressional correspondence: Senate, 1981 (Box-folder 4: 6-8)
    - Personal, 1981 January (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Personal, 1981 February (Box-folder 5: 2-3)
    - Personal, 1981 March (Box-folder 5: 4-6)
    - Personal, 1981 April (Box-folder 5: 7-9)
    - Personal, 1981 May (Box-folder 5: 10-11)
    - Personal, 1981 June (Box-folder 6: 1-3)
    - Personal, 1981 July (Box-folder 6: 4-6)
    - Personal, 1981 August (Box-folder 6: 7-9)
    - Personal, 1981 September (Box-folder 6: 10-11)
    - Personal, 1981 September (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - Personal, 1981 October (Box-folder 7: 2-5)
    - Personal, 1981 November (Box-folder 7: 6-7)
    - Personal, 1981 December (Box-folder 7: 8-10)
    - Personal, 1981 December (Box-folder 8: 1-3)
    - Official, 1981 January (Box-folder 8: 4-5)
    - Official, 1981 February (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - Official, 1981 February (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - Official, 1981 March (Box-folder 9: 2-5)
    - Official, 1981 April (Box-folder 9: 6-8)
    - Official, 1981 May (Box-folder 9: 9-11)
    - Official, 1981 June (Box-folder 10: 1-3)
    - Official, 1981 July (Box-folder 10: 4-5)
    - Official, 1981 August (Box-folder 10: 6-7)
    - Official, 1981 September (Box-folder 10: 8)
    - Official, 1981 October (Box-folder 10: 9-10)
    - Official, 1981 November (Box-folder 10: 11-12)
    - General, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 10: 13)
  - Alphabetical correspondence, 1968-1981. (Box-folder 11-18)
    Consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence dating from Allen's work in the Nixon White House and his tenure as Reagan's National Security Advisor. Arranged alphabetically by correspondent's last name.
    - A Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Allen outgoing memoranda, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 2)
    - Alsop, Stewart, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 3)
    - Anderson, Martina and Annelise, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - B Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 11: 5)
    - Baldwin, Hanson W., 1968 (Box-folder 11: 6)
    - Baroody, William Jr., 1968 (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - Bentley, Helen Delich, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 8)
    - Brandt, Willy (Minister), 1968 (Box-folder 11: 9)
    - Bennett, Wallace (Senator), 1968 (Box-folder 11: 10)
    - Buchanan, Patrick, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 11: 11)
    - Cahill, William T., 1969 (Box-folder 11: 12)
    - Caulfield, John J. (Jack), 1968-1969 (Box-folder 11: 13)
    - Chapin, Dwight, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 14)
    - Chennault, Mrs. Clair (Anne), 1968 (Box-folder 11: 15)
    - Cooper, John Sherman, 1968 (Box-folder 11: 16)
    - D Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 11: 17)
    - E Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 18)
    - Ehrlichman, John, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 19)
    - Ellsworth, Robert, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 20)
    - F Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 21)
    - Flanigan, Peter, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 22)
    - Flemming, Harry, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 11: 23)
    - G Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 24)
    - H Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 25)
    - Haig, Alexander, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 26)
    - Haldeman, H.R., 1969-1973 (Box-folder 11: 27)
    - Harlow, Bryce, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 28)
    - Huston, Tom Charles, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 11: 29)
    - K Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 11: 30)
    - Keogh, James, undated (Box-folder 11: 31)
    - King, John, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 11: 32)
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 12: 1-2)
    - Knight, Ridgeway B., 1969 (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - L Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - Lansdale, General Edward, 1968 (Box-folder 12: 5)
    - LeBailly, Major General E. B., 1969 (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - Lehman, John F., 1968-1969 (Box-folder 12: 1-7)
    - Lundquist, Darrel W., 1968-1969 (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - M Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - Mitchell, John, 1969 (Box-folder 12: 10)
    - Mollenhoff, Clark R., 1970 (Box-folder 12: 11)
    - N Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 12: 12)
    - Noble, Edward E., 1969 (Box-folder 12: 13)
    - O Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box-folder 12: 14)
    - Olds, Glenn A., 1969 (Box-folder 12: 15)
    - P Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 12: 16)
    - President Nixon, 1969 (Box-folder 12: 17)
    - Price, Raymond K., 1968 (Box-folder 12: 18)
    - Schlesinger, James R., 1968 (Box-folder 12: 19)
    - Strausz-Hope, Robert, 1969 (Box-folder 12: 20)
    - Takase, Tamotsu, 1969 (Box-folder 12: 21)
    - Teller, Dr. Edward, 1968 (Box-folder 12: 22)
    - Tower, John (Senator), 1968-1969 (Box-folder 12: 23)
    - Voegelin, Eric (Professor), 1968-1969 (Box-folder 12: 24)
    - Volle, Hermann, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 12: 25)
    - W Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 12: 26)
    - Wallace, Bruce A., 1969 (Box-folder 12: 27)
    - Woods, Rose Mary, 1969 (Box-folder 12: 28)
    - Ziegler, Ron, 1969 (Box-folder 12: 29)
    - Alphabetical correspondence, CLOSED, 1981 (Box-folder 13-18)
  - Public response to leave and resignation correspondence, 1981-1982. (Box-folder 19-21)
    Includes incoming and outgoing correspondence relating to Allen's administrative leave and resignation. Arranged in alphabetical order by correspondent's last name.
    - A, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 19: 1-2)
    - B, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 19: 3-5)
    - C, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 19: 6-8)
    - D, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 19: 9-10)
    - E, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 19: 11)
    - F, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 19: 12)
    - G, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 19: 13)
    - H, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - I-J, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - K, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 20: 4-5)
    - L, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - Mc, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 20: 7)
    - M, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 20: 8-10)
    - N, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 20: 11)
    - O, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 20: 12)
    - P-Q, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 20: 13-14)
    - R, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 21: 1-3)
    - S, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 21: 4-7)
    - T, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 21: 8)
    - U-V, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 21: 9)
    - W, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 21: 10-12)
    - X-Z, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 21: 13)
- Campaign and transition files, 1967-1984 (Box-folder 22-24)
  Contains correspondence, memoranda, press releases, clippings, interviews, notes, and speeches relating to political campaigns Allen worked on, including the Nixon and Reagan presidential campaigns and Allen's own run for governor of New Jersey. Arranged in three subseries: Nixon files, 1967-1969; New Jersey gubernatorial files, 1976-1977; Reagan files, 1967-1984.
  - Nixon files, 1967-1969. (Box-folder 22-26)
    Contains correspondence, memoranda, press releases, clippings, and speeches from the Richard Nixon presidential campaign of 1968. Also includes a small amount of material regarding selection of White House personnel. Allen served the campaign as senior foreign policy advisor. Arranged in chronological order.
    - Background material, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Richard M. Nixon Statements, 1967 (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - Richard M. Nixon Statements, 1968 January-March (Box-folder 22: 3)
    - Richard M. Nixon Statements, 1968 April (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - Richard M. Nixon Statements, 1968 May (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - Richard M. Nixon Statements, 1968 June (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - Richard M. Nixon Statements, 1968 July (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Richard M. Nixon Statements, 1968 August (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Richard M. Nixon Statements, 1968 September (Box-folder 22: 9-11)
    - Richard M. Nixon Statements, 1968 September (Box-folder 23: 1-2)
    - Richard M. Nixon Statements, 1968 October (Box-folder 23: 3-9)
    - Richard M. Nixon Statements, 1968 November 1-3 (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - Richard M. Nixon Statements: Post Election, 1968 (Box-folder 24: 10)
    - Log of Richard M. Nixon Statements, 1968 (Box-folder 24: 11)
    - Richard M. Nixon Acceptance Speech, 1968 (Box-folder 24: 12)
    - Memoranda, 1968 March-May (Box-folder 24: 1-3)
    - Memoranda, 1968 June (Box-folder 24: 4)
    - Memoranda, 1968 July (Box-folder 24: 5)
    - Memoranda, 1968 August (Box-folder 24: 6)
    - Memoranda, 1968 September (Box-folder 24: 7)
    - Memoranda, 1968 October (Box-folder 24: 8-9)
    - Memoranda, 1968 November (Box-folder 24: 10)
    - Nixon-Agnew Campaign Directory, 1968 (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - The Vice President, 1968 (Box-folder 25: 2)
    - 1968 Republican Platform (Box-folder 25: 3)
    - Convention, 1968 (Box-folder 25: 4)
    - Memoranda from Buchanan (DC Thoughts), 1968 (Box-folder 25: 5)
    - Staff, 1968 (Box-folder 25: 6)
    - Nixon on the Issues: Drafts, 1968 (Box-folder 25: 7-10)
    - Powelson, John P., 1968 (Box-folder 25: 11)
    - Campaign humor, 1968 (Box-folder 25: 12)
    - Foreign policy advisors and issues, 1968 (Box-folder 25: 13)
    - Glenn Olds: memoranda, 1968 (Box-folder 25: 14)
    - Glenn Olds: personnel model, 1968 (Box-folder 25: 15-16)
    - Press release: appointment to Nixon staff, 1968 (Box-folder 26: 1)
    - Pre-Election press, 1968 (Box-folder 26: 2)
    - Press, 1968 (Box-folder 26: 3-5)
    - U.S. News and World Report interview, 1968 November (Box-folder 26: 6)
    - Post-election press, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 26: 7-9)
    - The Nixon Yearbook, 1968 (Box-folder 26: 10)
    - Spring trip, 1969 (Box-folder 26: 11)
    - Press clippings regarding Allen's departure from National Security Council, 1969 October (Box-folder 26: 12)
  - New Jersey gubernatorial files, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 26)
    Correspondence, press releases, and clippings regarding Allen's run for New Jersey governor in 1976. Arranged in reverse chronological order.
    - Campaign file, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 26: 13)
  - Reagan files, 1967-1984. (Box-folder 27-42)
    Includes clippings, correspondence, statements, schedules, interviews, and notes dating from Ronald Reagan's presidential campaign in 1980, as well as a small amount of material from later campaigns. In addition to general material about Reagan as a candidate, the subseries also contains material about Allen as an advisor and focuses on foreign policy. Arranged by type of document into six subseries, then chronologically. Subseries are: Administrative files, 1977-1984; Correspondence, 1975-1980; Statements, debates, and interviews, 1977-1980; Policy files, 1967-1984; Press, 1976-1981; Transition, 1973-1981.
    - Administrative files, 1977-1984 (Box-folder 27)
      - Reagan for President Committee, 1979 (Box-folder 27: 1)
      - Phone logs, 1980 April-June (Box-folder 27: 2)
      - Schedules - RFP, 1980 (Box-folder 27: 3)
      - Thursday night group meetings, 1980 (Box-folder 27: 4)
      - Task force working copies, 1980 (Box-folder 27: 5)
      - Advisory groups: mailing lists, undated (Box-folder 27: 6)
      - Defense policy advisors, 1980 April 20 (Box-folder 27: 7)
      - Foreign policy advisors, 1980 April 20 (Box-folder 27: 8)
      - Foreign policy working groups, 1980 May 16 (Box-folder 27: 9)
      - Defense policy working groups, 1980 May 16 (Box-folder 27: 10)
      - Reagan meeting with foreign policy and defense advisors, 1980 May 16 (Box-folder 27: 11)
      - Foreign policy advisors, 1980 June 18 (Box-folder 27: 12)
      - Defense policy advisors, 1980 June 18 (Box-folder 27: 13)
      - Working groups: foreign policy, 1980 June 18 (Box-folder 27: 14)
      - Working groups: defense policy, 1980 June 18 (Box-folder 27: 15)
      - Campaign trip, Chicago, 1984 October 27 (Box-folder 27: 16)
      - CLOSED (Box-folder 36)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 27-29)
      - General (Box-folder 27)
        - 1980 Buildup correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 27: 17)
        - Disclaimer letter, 1980 (Box-folder 27: 18)
        - Correspondence - Mrs. Reagan, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 27: 19)
        - Correspondence - Europe, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 27: 20-21)
        - Advice/Opinion correspondence for Ronald Reagan, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 27: 22)
        - Washington office correspondence, 1979 (Box-folder 27: 23)
        - Foreign correspondence, 1980 (Box-folder 27: 24)
      - Alphabetical (Box-folder 27)
        - Allen, C. Carroll, 1980 (Box-folder 27: 24)
        - William Archer, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 27: 25)
        - William Casey, 1980 (Box-folder 27: 26)
        - Joe Churba, 1979 (Box-folder 27: 27)
        - Tony Dolan, undated (Box-folder 27: 28)
        - Bill Gavin, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 28: 1)
        - Stefan Halper and Roger Fontaine, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 28: 2)
        - Hannaford, 1978 (Box-folder 28: 3-4)
        - Hannaford - SP letters, 1978 (Box-folder 28: 5)
        - Pete Hannaford and Mike Deaver, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 28: 6)
        - Henry Hyde, 1979 July 27 (Box-folder 28: 7)
        - Fred Ikle, 1979 (Box-folder 28: 2)
        - Gary Jones, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 28: 3)
        - Marais, Pierre, undated (Box-folder 28: 4)
        - John Mclaughry, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 28: 5)
        - Ed Meese, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 28: 6)
        - John H. Morse, 1980 (Box-folder 28: 7)
        - Lev Nazarov, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 29: 1-2)
        - Eugene Rostow, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 29: 3-4)
        - Edward J. Rozek, 1980 (Box-folder 29: 5)
        - John Sears, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 29: 6)
        - Robert Strauzs-Hope, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 29: 7)